Luke Garnham 42 Oak Eggar Chase, Ipswich, Suffolk, IP8 3TJ 07776041530 | lukegarnham@msn.com

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a Mathematics graduate who has recently begun a Diploma in Software Development alongside my full-time job as an energy consultant. My course is self-funded through Code Institute where I am learning the fundamentals in Full Stack Web Development. I am studying part-time for 12 months with the ambition of completing the course by April 2021.

I have 7 years of experience working as an energy consultant and have progressed to the role of Data & Regulatory Analyst. I have been able to put my problem solving skills into practice, developed excellent MS Excel & VBA skills and I am now responsible for UK gas and power tenders.

My organised and thorough approach to work is suited to coding and whenever the opportunity to utilise VBA to solve problems has presented itself, I have thoroughly enjoyed the challenge. I am seeking opportunities to transition into a new and exciting career in software development where I can begin utilising my new skills as I continue to complete my qualification.

SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Strong IT Skills specialising in MS Excel
- Logical Thinker
- Strong Analytical Skills

- Fast Learner
- Organisation and Time Management
- Strong Communicator
- Team Player

EDUCATION

Code Institute (credit-rated by Edinburgh Napier University)

05/2020 - ongoing

Qualification: TBC in Diploma in Software Development

This Full Stack Software Development programme is credit-rated by Edinburgh Napier University. Some of the modules I will study include HTML & CSS fundamentals, user centric front-end development, JavaScript & Python fundamentals, data centric development and fullstack frameworks with Django. The content of the course is guided by an Industry Advisory Council consisting of "some of the top technology firms in the world" ensuring that the course content teaches "the most in-demand, industry-relevant skills". I have 12 months to complete 600 hours of online study in my own time and will complete 4 Milestone Projects which will formulate a portfolio.

University of Essex, Colchester, Essex

09/2007 - 07/2011

Qualification: 2:1 in Mathematics BSc

Key areas studied include calculus, statistics, numerical methods and optimisation. My final year project focused in the area of optimisation which further developed my research and problem solving abilities. I gained knowledge and experience in computer programming. I was determined to succeed and feel my effort was rewarded and reflected with a much valued qualification.

Copleston High School Sixth Form, Ipswich, Suffolk

09/2005 - 07/2007

Qualification: 3 A-levels & 3 AS-levels

I gained three A-levels including Mathematics and Design & Technology, plus three AS-levels including Further Mathematics and Physics.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Kinect Energy UK Ltd (formerly UX Energy Services), Ipswich

07/2013 - Present

Data & Regulatory Analyst, Operations Team

My current role is very varied and sees me leading UK flexible tendering and writing quarterly regulatory reports covering industry updates affecting non-energy costs. I am responsible for creating Gas and Power budgets for UK clients, forecasting non-energy costs, Triad forecasting, supporting fixed price tenders and attending meetings with suppliers. Many of these tasks require strong analytical skills, attention to detail and working to deadlines. When approaching problems, I aim to produce solutions which are repeatable, scalable and can be automated as much as possible.

into Education Ltd, Bury St Edmunds, Suffolk

08/2011 - 07/2013

Inbound Programme Manager

Working directly under the UK Manager, I was responsible for running the UK branch of a foreign student exchange organisation, I gained experience and exposure to all levels of the business. I was responsible for managing a team of coordinators across the UK, often working under pressure to meet deadlines and making important decisions to ensure approximately 200 students arriving annually would have a suitable host family and a place in a nearby school.

Sainsbury's, Ipswich, Suffolk

10/2006 - 11/2010

Cashier & Stock Control

This was a part-time role I undertook whilst studying for my A-level's and Degree.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I enjoy "Escape the Room" games and in recent years taught myself to play the guitar. I attend a gym several times a week to keep fit. I enjoy going on walks and I am a season ticket holder at Ipswich Town FC.

OTHER

Clean Driving Licence

Trained First Aider

Course Representative: I was a representative for my year group during University, attending departmental meetings each term on behalf of my peers.

President and Treasurer of a University sports club: I earned a Sports Recognition award from the University for my contribution over 3 years.

REFERENCES

References are available on request.